welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
okay
welcome to the mega mastermind what do
we do here well this is our tagline we
this is a an ongoing experiment where
we're prototyping digital gangs to help
people maintain their sovereignty and
respond to the meta crisis and that last
point is in reference to what I was just
saying about some of the existential
risks being faced by humanity right now
and the digital gangs component is
basically small little units of
community that bring people together in
a way that can be useful in response to
some of these threats but we're not
going to talk about the threats tonight
we're going to talk more about community
before I get into any of that
just a reminder these sessions tend to
be smaller so I really encourage people
to turn on their video and to use the
chat feel free to use it while I'm
talking and chat with each other have a
parallel conversation and really make
friends because if we're just getting
information here and we're not building
relationships then that's a performative
contradiction and I don't want to be
complicit in that so I'm pushing
everybody to lean into relationships
I'll say this every week the other thing
is we have a writing crew because
there's a lot of really interesting
thinkers in this space that want to put
their ideas into some form of public
sense making artifact on Eastern time we
meet at 6:30 a.m. every weekday and
someone's going to share that link in
the chat if you're interested it's one
hour you just jump into a zoom room and
you're right in which we put our writing
intentions and we hold each other
accountable for the hour and there's
also a slack channel for the
conversation to continue so you'll also
see that link in the chat okay tonight's
structure we're gonna talk about
authentic relating and how it relates to
the metagame
and how it relates to this masterminding
project that we're exploring here and
then we're gonna do it we're gonna go
into breakout rooms and we're gonna
experiment and experiment with something
called the noticing game which I'll
explain and depending on how many rounds
we do that for we'll have some time for
a group chat at the end so this is going
to be quite participatory I'm hoping to
shut up after a few minutes so
you wanted to just you know listen and
not be involved and you kind of came to
the wrong zooom room but I encourage you
to stay because it's gonna be good so
let's do a quick introduction to tie
everything back together to what the
theme of this weekly session is because
I know there's some new faces here first
of all what is a mastermind you know
we're calling this the metagame
mastermind a lot of you may have heard
this term I think it goes back and
pulling Hill it's kind of like a
self-help term a friendly alliance with
one or more persons who will encourage
one to follow through with both plan and
purpose so it's basically an
accountability group right when people
care whether or not you show up or care
whether or not you are doing the things
you say you will do the probability that
you will do those things goes up and so
if you have a little tried like that
that's holding you together that
actually helps raise your sovereignty
and that's the mastermind we have a
different slightly different take on
this but you'll see as I share more how
it fits into what we're doing tonight
tonight is this weekly Saturday session
called the metagame mastermind where we
explore a bunch of different topics
related to masterminding related to
everything really that has to do with
relationships and developing sovereignty
and our response to reality so it's
quite a broad topic and that is a weekly
event that occurs in the stoah which is
a series of you know a bunch of
different weekly events and ad-hoc
events what you don't see here and what
you won't see in the stoah are all the
triads groups of three that have spun
off of these Saturday sessions and these
are little mastermind groups and I like
calling them digital gangs because a lot
of these people are in different time
zones and they're just meeting only on
zoom' because of the pandemic and these
are three sometimes there's four people
somehow there's two people but generally
they're three person groups many of
which are in this room right now that
are doing this whole accountability
thing so that's just some context for
what's going on here if you're
interested in this I will share my email
at the end and I can give you guys a
chance to sign up for one of those
triads so that's a mastermind what isn't
what is the metagame this is actually a
really elusive concept that has some
buzz and you see it a lot in Twitter but
here's a definition I really like
playing the meta game helps us discover
the right relationship with the ecology
of games we are
currently playing so it's basically an
analogy to think about life as a series
of games and then to occupy the position
where you have the most sovereignty over
all those games and then you can reflect
on do I want to be a part of this game
do I want to opt out of this one you
want to play that game that I'm not
playing right now or how do I play this
game better because I'm realizing it's
one of the more important games so at
the very least that's the meta game it's
a position of reflection on all the
other games but it's more than that
which we'll come back to in other
sessions but for the sake of tonight
this that's the definition of the meta
game and some of these games that might
come in with the mastermind are games
having to do with like your finances or
your career or romance or you know all
these things buzzwords that we've
written here all these different games
that a mastermind group can actually
help you play better now this is a set
up for tonight the game that we're going
to focus on is authentic relating which
in itself is kind of meta because
authentic relating for those of you
don't know it's a term that it has now
become something of a movement that has
kind of specific instantiations that
refer to the process of relating to each
other more authentically it's like you
can just take it at at the level of the
name and relating to each other
authentically is necessary for
successful mastermind groups if you just
want to hold each other accountable you
need some level of authenticity but if
you want to play the metagame mastermind
then you up regulate your authenticity a
little bit and why why am I saying why
is this important oh and this is the
most important part basically this isn't
getting into right relationship with
each other
antek relating is a practice for doing
that I put this image here I'm pretty
sure many of you have seen this this is
a piece of art from one of the burning
man's a few years ago
which shows I think something that a lot
of us often feel right where for
whatever reason may be in authenticity
the inner child or the more authentic
parts of ourselves have difficulty
reaching the authentic parts of others
and you might be wondering why any of
this matters right well this isn't this
about accountability like why are we
talking about authentic relating but why
are we talking about our feelings and
authenticity well the reason is
because as this incredible person once
said the meaning of life is friends and
this is something I've been thinking a
lot about lately
until I treated this very recently the
meaning of life is not accountability
groups the meaning of life is not your
career it's not and maybe this is my
opinion but I'm just gonna go with it
it's not cultivating personal
sovereignty I mean those are good things
but if we make that the meaning of life
there's something kind of perverted
about it why would we cultivate personal
sovereignty if if we're in a relational
vacuum and the more and more I think
about this more I realize that it's
ultimately none of this makes sense if
there's no friendship if there's no
relation if there's no other and I want
to take us down that path more and more
tonight so one of the things that stops
us from actually one realizing that the
meaning of life is friends and feel free
to disagree with me on this but if you
play with this for a second you'll
realize that we we don't always think
like this you know we often make
decisions at the expense of our
friendships in service of other things
that supposedly are more meaningful than
our friendships than our relationships
one of the things that keeps coming up
that gets in the way of genuine
friendship authentic relating is
something called impression management
which we talked about two weeks ago and
we're gonna riff on this a few I think
in in coming weeks as well and basically
this is a conscious or unconscious
process in which we attempt to influence
the perceptions of the other people
around us about ourselves it's that you
you kind of hold back information and
you're trying to make yourself seem
cooler than you are or you try to make
yourself seem more powerful than you are
or whatever and it can be conscious we
can be morally agnostic about it
sometimes impression management might
actually be useful but unfortunately
oftentimes it's unconscious and our
impressions create this persona that
stand in the way of authentic relating
so we've explored in the past some ways
to break through this and tonight we're
gonna explore another one and again I
want to remind us of at the goal right
underneath the idea of the purpose of
life being friends is the idea that
ultimately we were seeking connection or
connectedness and
I'm sure many of you are familiar with
Bernie Brown and I love this quote in
order for connection to happen we have
to allow ourselves to be seen an
impression management is when you're
throttling that potential to be seen
when you're putting something else
you're introducing your own agenda in
the way of that and again this isn't
necessarily bad but I think it's it's
unfortunate when it's happening
unconsciously so this is what we're
gonna lean into in this breakout session
and if you're feeling a little bit
nervous about it that's probably a good
sign because this this is you know gonna
be a little bit awkward it's called the
noticing game and I'm going to explain
the rules and then I'm gonna demo it and
then I'll give everyone a chance to ask
some questions so the structure is super
super simple
it's two people in the zoom room one
person is person a the others person B
you can go alphabetically and person a
goes first and says what I noticed when
I'm with you is and then they fill in
the blank and then person B says hearing
that what I'm noticing is and then they
fill in the blank and you go back and
forth and you do this for five minutes
and the idea is that you only say things
that you are noticing this creates
something like a conversational
meditation where I say something that
I'm noticing you say something that
you're noticing and then we both are
attending to only things that are
happening right now and that starts to
peel back impression management to some
extent it's definitely still gonna be
there and to some extent it should be
because you know you're gonna meet some
stranger's and you want to keep yourself
somewhat guarded but it also opens up
the door to actually be seen and that
opens up the door to relate to each
other more authentically some of the
things you can say some of the things
you can notice you can notice the other
person's physical appearance when I'm
with you I noticed that you seem to be
looking away a lot sensations in your
own body I notice I'm feeling nervous
tension in my chest thoughts you're
having I noticed that I'm curious about
how you got that scar on your forehead
emotions you're feeling I notice that
I'm grateful that we're getting to have
this experience together I'm gonna share
all this in the chat or somebody else
might someone else who might have it so
don't worry about remembering this stuff
but it's gonna be something that you're
seeing something
physical something that you're
experiencing as a sensation something
that you're thinking a thought a piece
of language and something that is just
an emotion and now we're gonna demo this
so that it makes a little more sense all
right
so Khalil would you like to do a couple
rounds of the noticing game